universalclass.com 2019-12-05

# Privacy Policy

**Universal Class, Inc. takes your privacy seriously.** Please feel free to review our Privacy Policy: 

Because we want to provide you with the most efficient, enhanced, and secured service, we may request information about you. This Privacy Policy outlines your privacy rights for using UniversalClass service and lets you know how we ("UniversalClass") collect, use, store and otherwise share information you have provided us in order to use our services. 

This Privacy Policy in conjunction with our Terms of service as well as any other agreements or policies provided by UniversalClass governs your use of our services.

If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, our Terms of Service, or any other agreements or policy that governs use of our service, you should not use any of our services. 

**About this Privacy Policy**

  * This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of personally identifiable information that we collect when you are anywhere on our sites, and when you use any of our services. 
  * This policy does not apply to the practices of companies, schools, or other organizations that we not own or control, or to people that we do not manage or employ. UniversalClass contains several links to other sites and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those sites. 

**Summary of Information We Collect and Track**

  * **General Usage Information**. UniversalClass collects information about all users collectively, such as what areas users visit and what services members use. This data is automatically retrieved. This type of general information is not used to identify specific users, but in an aggregate form to help us analyze traffic patterns and enhance our service to better serve our users and advertisers. 
  * **UniversalClass Member Registration**. When you register on any site or service provided by UniversalClass, we ask for personal information from you such as a username, first name, last name, email address, password, country and other related information. This information is required in order to provide a course to you as well as secure and store your course progress and potential course completion. When you log in to our services with your username and password (that identifies your registration data), you are not anonymous to us. Both General Usage Information and any personal details you provide to us is used to enhance and customize content, identify (and in some cases validate) you when you post or share content, participate in a class, or access any of our member-privileged services. 
  * **Creating, Joining, Taking, or Using our Virtual Classroom Environment**. When you create, join, take, or use our Virtual Classroom Environment, you are not anonymous to us, the instructor(s) within the class, or the student(s) within the class you have enrolled. Personally and identifiable information about you such as your UniversalClass username, your first and last name, and your email address is made available to our staff, instructors, proctors and other course facilitators in order to both help and assess your course progress. This information is used to better enhance your online education experience and to promote free and open inquiry as well as to hold class participants personally responsible for their work and behavior within the online class. You do have the option of sharing your course work and other identifiable information about yourself to fellow course participants. Should you choose to do this, we are **not responsible** of how fellow class participants decide to use this information about you. 

**Information We Collect Using Automated Processes**

When you access any part of our service, including browsing our website, reviewing articles, and/or reviewing our course catalog and course listings, we collect technical information through automated means. This information may include without limitation: 

  * Technical information about the device or computer you’re using to access our services, such as date/time of visit, device type, your IP address, operating system information, browser, browser language, information accessed, and other systems information; and
  * Usage statistics about your interaction with our services, including pages visited, courses accessed, time spent on pages or the services, pages visited, search queries, click data, portions of the services used, date and time, and other information regarding your use of the services.

This collected data through automated means may also be linked to your information and is provided using server log files and tracking technologies. The primary data collection technologies UniversalClass uses are as follows: 

  * Cookies. A "cookie" is a small piece of information sent by a web server to store on a web browser so it can later be read back from that browser. This is useful for having the browser remember some specific information and to help maintain "state". A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other websites. We may use cookies to help identify you when you visit our site. All of our member-privileged services require the use of cookies. While you may opt to disable cookies on your browser, our service will not work correctly or at all.
  * Web beacons. A web beacon is a small object that allows us to determine what actions visitors of our service perform when using our service.
  * Server logs. When you make a request for something hosted on our service (directly or indirectly), such activity is logged. This logging includes technical information, such as the date/time of request, your IP address, page/item accessed, your computer type, browser type, and other technical information. 

**A Note About Cookies**

UniversalClass and other third-party data collection tools such as Google Analytics (and/or other third party advertisers) may use scripts, server logs, cookies, web beacons or other data collection tools when you access or use any of our services. We may correlate this information gathered by these means to other information about you as described in this Privacy Policy. 

We may use web beacons or other data collection technologies in order for us to determine if a specific page or service was opened, accessed, or activated and/or to determine what promotions to offer a user.

We use cookies in order to allow you to login to our service, improve the functionality of our service, collect and analyze usage of our service so we can improve it, provide a personalized experience of our service, prevent fraud and abuse on our service, customize your experience of our service, and help provide a more efficient delivery of our service.

For example, UniversalClass may use cookies for any of the following reasons:

  * Essential cookies. These cookies are essential for our website to function. These cookies secure your credentials when you log in to our service. They also help protect your account against unauthorized access and helps to fight abuse and fraud. 
  * Statistics and Measurement cookies. These cookies allow us to count visitors, visits, pages viewed, etc. They help us improve how our website functions.
  * Tracking/targeting cookies. These cookies record your visits, links followed, and pages viewed. We use this information to make the site relevant to your interests. 
  * Security. We use cookies to secure your credentials when you log in to our service. These cookies help protect your account against unauthorized access and helps to fight abuse and fraud.
  * Customization. We use cookies to customize your experience of our service by remembering your preferences on how our service looks and behaves to fit your individual preferences.
  * Maintain State. We use session cookies to maintain your current state (in order to determine if you are currently logged in) and be able to show you purchases made, courses you are currently taking or have completed, and provide account-specific information.

You may set your browser to disable cookies from a website. You will need to review your specific browser documentation regarding how to disable cookies. If you do disable cookies from our service, then our service will not work properly, and you will not be able to access member-specific services, such as taking courses. 

By using any of our services, you consent to the use of cookies, web beacons and any other data collection tools we may use as described in this Privacy Policy. 

**Third Party Analytics Tracking**

UniversalClass uses the following third-party tracking services on our service: Google Analytics. This service may use data collection technologies such as cookies and web beacons. These analytics services help us determine how users interact and use our service and/or how users found our service (for example, by clicking on various ads or other website links that connect to our website). This information collected on our behalf by these third-party analytics services help us improve our services as well as to understand how people use our services. 

UniversalClass uses Google to measure the performance of its advertising. To measure advertising performance, Google uses small strings of text (known as cookies) that are placed on your computer when you click on our ads. Cookies typically remain active on your computer for about 30 days. If you visit certain pages of the UniversalClass's website during that period, Google and UniversalClass will be able to tell that you saw the ad delivered by Google. If you'd like to know more about how Google handles information gathered from the use of cookies, please read their [privacy policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy.html). You may opt out of Google Analytics by downloading the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.

UniversalClass may use third-party advertising technologies to deliver marketing information and advertisements about our services to you on other websites or online applications. These ads may be tailored to your interests based on the content of a page you visited, searches you may have conducted, various demographic information provided by server logs and/or web beacons, and/or activity you may have done over time across different websites.

We use third parties advertising and analytic services (such as advertising networks and advertising servers including but not limited to Google Analytics, DoubleClick and others) to help deliver these tailored advertisements on other websites and online applications. These third-party advertising services may place cookies or other tracking technologies on your computer or other online-enabled. These third-party advertising services may access these cookies that they have placed on your device or use other tracking technologies in order to serve these advertisements.

We do not have access to nor does our Privacy Policy govern the use of cookies or other tracking technologies that may be placed on your computer or device from these non-affiliated, third-party entities. Third parties that use these technologies may offer you a way of opting out of advertising tracking and targeting. For example, to opt out of Google Analytics for display advertising or customize Google display network ads, you may visit the Google Ads Settings [page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). We do not control any of the third-party advertising services and companies and we have no control over whether any company chooses to participate in advertising opt-out programs. 

**What We Do with Collected Data**

UniversalClass may use information we collect for the following reasons:

  * General statistics, traffic analysis, and site usage.
  * Order fulfillment. We require personal information such as full name, email, address and other details in order to verify online payments and fulfill orders and subscription purchases. Data collected from UniversalClass members (people who have filled out our registration form and logged in) is used to identify the member in order to allow that member to join and participate in our online classes.
  * Course progress and course completion. We use collected information in order to track your course progress, assessments, and course completions.
  *  Communications. We use collected information to facilitate communication between you and instructors, course facilitators, staff, and other students.
  *  Security. We use collected information to both identify you and secure your account.
  *  Account preferences. We use collected information to allow you set your account preferences.
  * Provide support. We use collected information in order to provide customers with support and resolve issues.
  * Analyze usage and traffic. We use collected information in order to analyze service usage and traffic.
  * Advertise. We may used collected information to advertise additional products and services.
  * Prevent abuse. We use collected information to identify and prevent fraud and abuse of our service.
  *  Customize service. We use collected information to customize various parts of our service.

**Sharing of Information We Collect**

UniversalClass will share your information that we have collected (such as registration information, coursework, and/or course progress/completion information) with the following third-parties:

**Instructors and Course Facilitators:**

Your account information that we have collected will be shared with course instructors and course facilitators so that they can properly assess your course progress and answer any course-related questions. 

**Business Partners, Contractors and/or Agents:**

UniversalClass may hire or partner with other companies to perform certain functions and in these instances, we may share your information with these third-party companies. For example, we may hire third-party companies for payment processing, order fulfillment, marketing services, data analysis, hosting services, and support.

UniversalClass may partner with other organizations and/or business to train their patrons or employees. When we partner with another company to perform these functions, we may provide collected information to the partner showing how their employees or patrons are using the service. If you are accessing UniversalClass service through a business partner (such as a library or through your employer), this Privacy Policy does not govern their use of your Information; you will need to review their Privacy Policy in these cases. 

**Other UniversalClass Members:**

If you engage in sending/accepting contacts, email other course participants, post to the Class discussion forums, opt to share any course completion awards, and/or set your profile to be viewable by the public, then this information may be accessible to the general public. Additionally, if you ask a question or send a comment to an instructor or course facilitator, information such as your full name may be publicly viewable by others. UniversalClass is not responsible for information you choose to make public on its web sites, and if you do not want this information to be public, select to use this service "privately" in the "Account Settings" area or the "Privacy Settings" area. It is equally important to note that if you choose to use our Virtual Classroom Environment (by either creating, teaching, joining, or using one or any of our online classes) some personally identifiable information is released about you to class participants. This information is limited to your first and last name (the name you entered when you signed up on UniversalClass), email address, and your UniversalClass username and any other information you decide to share to the public.

**Business Transfers:**

Although unlikely, UniversalClass may sell its businesses or assets. In transactions such as these, customer information is generally one of the transferred business assets. Should UniversalClass or one of its business lines be sold, customer information may be one of the transferred assets.

**Your Permission:**

We may share information with third parties outside the scope of this Privacy Policy if you have specifically authorized us to do so.

**Non-disclosure of Your Personal Data**

We will not sell, share, or otherwise distribute your Personal Data to third parties except as provided in this Privacy Policy. We may disclose your Personal Data to other Universal Class affiliates worldwide that agree to treat it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Personal Data may also be transferred to third parties who act for or on our behalf, for further processing in accordance with the purpose(s) for which the data were originally collected or may otherwise be lawfully processed, such as services delivery, evaluating the usefulness of this website, marketing, data management and/or technical support. These third parties have contracted with UniversalClass to only use Personal Data for the agreed upon purposes, and not to sell your Personal Information to third parties, and not to disclose it to third parties except as may be required by law, as permitted by us or as stated in this Privacy Policy. 

Personal Data collected from you may also be transferred to a third party in the event that the company and the customer data connected with it is sold or transferred, in which case we would require the buyer or transferee to treat any Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

Personal Data may also be disclosed to a third party if required by applicable law, court order, or government regulation, or if such disclosure is otherwise necessary in support of any criminal or other legal investigation or proceeding. 

**Security of Information We Collect**

We work hard to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts any sensitive or financial information you submit. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to log off when finished using a shared computer. 

**Selecting a Public Profile**

If you decide to create or update your profile to be " **public** " then your areas of interest, course completions, your full name, and any other information you may have submitted about yourself will be made public to UniversalClass members, as well as the Internet, and as well as the general public. By making your profile "public" you completely accept that personal information about yourself is no longer made private and you are no longer considered "anonymous". UniversalClass is not responsible for how others may use information you set to be public.

**Our Commitment to Children's Privacy**

Protecting the privacy of the very young is extremely important to us. For this reason, we do not collect or maintain information at our website from anyone who identifies themselves as being under the age of 13 in the U.S. or under 16 in the European Economic Area. UniversalClass is an adult service for adult learners. If you have knowledge of someone using our service under the age of 13 in the U.S. or under the age of 16 in the European Economic Area, please contact us at privacyhelp@universalclass.com so we can take steps to remove the account and associated information. 

**How You Can Access or Correct Your Information**

If you have registered on the UniversalClass service, you have access to your personally identifiable information. You can update or correct this information under "My UniversalClass" by clicking on the link "[Edit Profile](https://members.universalclass.com/myclasses/secure/profile.htm)". Your profile is unique and secured by your Universal Class Username and Password. 

**Removing Your Account**

If you would like to remove your account and registration information from our service, you may do so by logging into “My Classes”, selecting the menu item “Account Settings” and pressing the button “Account Removal”. Follow the procedures outlined there to verify and complete your account removal request.

If you are having issues with removing your account on our service, please contact your helpdesk directly for help: <https://www.universalclass.com/helpdesk>

Please note that removing your account does not remove any content you may have posted, comments you may have sent, submissions you may have made, or emails you may have sent. Removing your account does not remove any information that you may have been posted or sent through a Third-Party Platform (such as Facebook). Even after your account has been deleted (or terminated), we may retain your information for as long as we have a legitimate purpose to do so and in accordance with applicable law in order to assist with any legal obligations, prevent fraud and abuse, enforce our agreements and policies, and/or resolve disputes. 

**Release of Student Records**

Once you have completed an online course, your student records are available for up to 7 years from the date of completion in the form of an online certificate (if you purchased the certificate option), and available under the "My Transcripts" area. You personally control and are responsible for any release of this information to other parties. You can set whether or not your certificate is available to other people using the 'Share My Award' feature located on the online version of your certificate. For example, you can select whether or not it is private (viewable only by you) or public (viewable to anyone) and/or whether it is password protected (viewable only to people who have the password). 

**Our Commitment to Data Security**

UniversalClass.com has taken several security measures in order to protect the information under our control. All personal information we collect is stored on machines owned by UniversalClass, Inc. at a secured location in order to ensure that no unauthorized individuals have access to the equipment or its data. 

**Option to Discontinue Direct Communications**

If you would like to discontinue communications with our company, simply submit your request to our online helpdesk: <https://www.universalclass.com/helpdesk> \-- please include your name, email address registered on the site, and username along with the removal request. Removal requests are usually processed within 1-2 business days. 

**If You Reside Outside the United States**

Universal Class, Inc. is a U.S. company and its headquarters are located in Florida. In order for Universal Class, Inc. to provide any services to you, your data must be transferred and processed within the United States. By visiting any of our websites or using any of our services, you consent to the storage of your data on servers that are located within the United States. If you are using using any of our services from outside the United States, you agree to the transfer, storage, and processing of your data in the United States (or other countries). Specifically, personal data collected in Switzerland and the European Economic Area (EEA) is transferred and stored outside of those areas. By submitting your data (filling out a web form, registering for a course, making payments, etc.) or by using any part of our services, you agree to this transfer, storage, and processing of your data that may be outside your country. 

**How to Contact Us**

Universal Class, Inc. is committed to protecting your privacy. If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please contact privacyhelp@universalclass.com. 

### UniversalClass Cookie Policy

A Note About Cookies 

A "cookie" is a small piece of information sent by a web server to store on a web browser so it can later be read back from that browser. This is useful for having the browser remember some specific information and to help maintain "state". For example, we may use cookies to help identify you when you visit our site. All our member-privileged services require the use of cookies. While you may opt to disable cookies on your browser, our service will not work correctly or at all. 

UniversalClass and other third-party data collection tools such as Google Analytics (and other third party advertisers) may use scripts, server logs, cookies, web beacons or other data collection tools when you access or use any of our services. We may correlate this information gathered by these means to other information about you as described in our [Privacy Policy](https://www.universalclass.com/myinterests/privacypolicy.htm). For example, we may use web beacons or other data collection technologies in order for us to determine if a specific page or service was opened, accessed, or activated and/or to determine what promotions to offer a user. 

Why Does UniversalClass Use Cookies and Other Data Collection Technologies? 

We use cookies in order to allow you to login to our service, improve the functionality of our service, collect and analyze usage of our service so we can improve it, provide a personalized experience of our service, prevent fraud and abuse on our service, customize your experience of our service, and help provide a more efficient delivery of our service. For example, UniversalClass may use cookies for any of the following reasons: 

  * General statistics, traffic analysis, and site usage.
  * Security. We use cookies to secure your credentials when you log in to our service. These cookies help protect your account against unauthorized access and helps to fight abuse and fraud or any activity that violates our terms and agreements.
  * Customization. We use cookies to customize your experience of our service by remembering your preferences on how our service looks and behaves to fit your individual preferences.
  * Maintain State. We use session cookies to maintain your current state (in order to determine if you are currently logged in) and be able to show you purchases made, courses you are currently taking or have completed, and provide account-specific information.

You may set your browser to disable cookies from a website. You will need to review your specific browser documentation regarding how to disable cookies. If you do disable cookies from our service, then our service will not work properly, and you will not be able to access member-specific services, such as taking courses. 

By using any of our services, you consent to the use of cookies, web beacons and any other data collection tools we may use as described in our [Privacy Policy](https://www.universalclass.com/myinterests/privacypolicy.htm). 

**Your Cookie Opt-Out Choices**

To opt-out of Google Analytics or Google Advertising, please contact Google directly: [Google Opt-Out](https://policies.google.com/technologies/managing).

If you'd like to delete cookies or instruct your web browser to delete or refuse cookies, please visit the help section of your web browser. Please note that disabling cookies will remove your ability to take any courses and will cause the website to not function correctly. 

Additional Help 

If you have any additional questions regarding our use of cookies, you may contact us at privacyhelp@universalclass.com.
